Will Parker

Undergraduate Student Chicago, IL mrwillparker@icloud.com

Education

Northern Illinois University

DeKalb, IL 2020 - 2024

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

- GPA: 3.571

Relevant Coursework: Signals and Systems, Electronic Circuits, Embedded Systems, Electromagnetics,
Control Systems, Biomedical Instrumentation, Communication Networks, Solid-State Devices

Personal Statement

My engineering interests include biomedical electronics and signal processing, but I am open to all fields of electrical and computer engineering such as semiconductors and embedded systems. I have plentiful experience in leadership positions and teamwork, so I am confident I will make a positive contribution to your company. My best qualities include being able to account for my responsibilities and beyond, all while maintaining an excellent end product in a time-efficient manner.

Work Experience

Northern Illinois University: Department of Physics

DeKalb, IL

PHYS 273 Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Apr. 2022 - Present

- Organize problem-solving lectures for second semester of calculus-based physics.
- Provide additional tutoring and lessons for underrepresented groups.
- Complete supplementary courses in methods of science education.

Office of Student Engagement and Experiential Learning (NIU)

DeKalb, IL

Undergraduate Research Ambassador

July 2022 - Present

- Selected from a competitive pool of undergraduate research candidates.
- Lead cohorts of first-time undergraduate research students.
- Coordinate workshops and presentations for professional development.

Research Experience

Northern Illinois University: Department of Physics

DeKalb, IL

Undergraduate Researcher

Jan. 2023 - Present

- Working under Dr. Laurence Lurio and Dr. Michael Eads to track attendance rates of students enrolled in PHYS 273 for the Spring 2023 semester.
- The attendance rates will be compared to student learning outcomes, as measured by exam scores, final course grades, and performance on the same pre-course and post-course survey exam.

Northern Illinois University: Department of History

DeKalb, IL

Undergraduate Researcher

Aug. 2021 - May 2022

- Worked under the guidance of Dr. Beatrix Hoffman to create a historical timeline of the occurence of depersonlization and derealization disorder
- Cataloged the changes in the diagnostic criteria as defined by the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders throughout its revisions.
- Presented findings at the Conference on Undergraduate Research and Engagement.

Awards, Grants & Honours

Northern Illinois University Presidential Scholar (\$30,000)	2020
Office of Student Engagement and Experiential Learning Award (\$1000)	2022
Undergraduate Research Assistant Award (\$500)	2021

Skills

- Programming and Markup Languages

* **Expert:** C, C++, Python

* Intermediate: Java, JavaScript, CSS, SQL

Software

* Expert: Quartus Prime, LTspice, MATLAB, Arduino, MS Office Applications

* Intermediate: Maple, Mathematica

- Foreign Languages

* Fluent: Spanish

* Conversational: Portugese, French